理查德  你都穿好衣服了
Richard, you're dressed.
这不都早上了吗
Well, it is morning, isn't it?
只是你被禁止跟凯瑟琳
Well, it's just that ever since you were banned
一起办案之后
from working cases with Katherine,
你就经常一身睡衣在家
you and your pajamas have seen an awful lot of each other.
我觉得你太夸张了吧
I think you're exaggerating.
我的确偶尔放松身心  恢复精神
I admit I've taken the occasional day off to recharge,
但也不该说我就...
but I hardly think it's fair.
卡塞尔  你都穿好衣服了啊
Wow. Castle, you're dressed?
是的  我穿好了
Yes, I'm dressed.
没想到你们会这么小题大做
I did not think it would be such an event.
早上好  亲爱的
Good morning, babe.
你是为今天做了什么特别的安排吗
Does this mean you have something special planned for today?
事实上  我今天还真有特别的事
As a matter of fact, I do have something special lined up...
是一个给你准备的惊喜
A surprise, actually, for you.
真的  什么样的惊喜
Really? What kind of a surprise?
如果我说了  不就不是惊喜了
Well, now, if I told you that, it wouldn't be a surprise.
相信我  你会喜欢的
But trust me, you're gonna love it.
我为什么会觉得害怕呢
Okay, now, why does that scare me?
因为你聪明啊
Because you're smart.
得了  卡塞尔  说吧
Hmm. Come on, Castle... spill.
你这样的审讯大师
A master interrogator like yourself,
就这点本事吗
and that's the best you've got?
或许我这才刚开始呢
Maybe I'm just getting started.
看来不行了
Or not.
被害人是莎娜·贝克
Victim is Shana Baker.
从工资单来看
According to her pay stubs,
她是伊斯特本幼儿园的老师
she worked at Eastbourne Preschool.
凶手是从她卧室的窗户进来的
Point of entry - is the window in her bedroom.
有人敲碎了窗户
Somebody broke the glass.
那她肯定应该能听到
She would have heard that.
从她尸体的姿态来看
And based on her body position,
她似乎没有想逃的意思
it doesn't look like she was trying to run away.
的确
No, she wasn't.
毫无防卫伤或挣扎的迹象
No signs of defensive wounds or a struggle.
一枪中胸
Just a single gunshot to the chest.
所以她回到家时  凶手已经在等她了
Which means our killer was in here when she came home.
如此聪明的女人怎么会自愿嫁给卡塞尔呢
How a woman so astute could choose to marry Castle.
得了  帕穆特  承认吧
Ah, come on, Perlmutter, admit it.
-你也想他了吧  -得了
- You miss him, too. - Please.
一想到他不会再出现在这儿
Just knowing he's not gonna be here
就觉得上班简直太美好了
makes coming to work sheer bliss...
惨剧除外
...All things considered.
死亡时间
Time of death?
从尸斑和肝脏温度来看
Well, lividity and liver temp suggest
是昨晚9点到10点30之间
between 9:00 and 10:30 last night.
邻居不在  应该是因此才
The neighbors were out, which is probably why
没人听到枪声  但鉴证组找到了这个
no one heard the shot, but CSU did find this.
香烟头
A cigarette butt.
嗯
Yeah.
在卧室窗户外的消防梯上
It was in the fire escape outside the bedroom window.
楼上楼下的邻居都不抽烟
The neighbors above and below are not smokers.
被害人也不是
Neither was the victim,
牙齿这么白不可能吸烟
not with pearly whites like these.
如果凶手还有时间抽烟
So if our killer had time to grab a smoke,
那就不是擅闯民宅
Then this wasn't a b&e.
凶手是在等待她回来
Our killer was lying in wait, which means...
那么这就是预谋杀人了
this was premeditated.
狗哪去了
Where's the dog?
不见了
Dog's gone.
可能是被枪声吓跑了
Might have been scared off by the gunshot.
或者  闪闪像灵犬莱西一样
Or, like Lassie, Sparkles is out there,
正在外找凶手呢
trying to track down our killer.
不是吧  莱西
Really? Lassie?
卡塞尔走了  总得有人来
Someone has to provide us with out-of-the-box thinking
提出比较新奇的看法
now that Castle's not around.
谢了  不过我还是自己来吧
Thank you. But I'll take it from here.
卡塞尔  你怎么来了
Castle? What are you doing?
你知道你不能来的
You know that you're not allowed to be here.
其实  我可以
Actually, I am,
因为我已经不是理查德·卡塞尔
because I'm no longer Richard Castle,
普通市民了
ordinary citizen.
我现在  是理查德·卡塞尔
I am now Richard Castle...
私家侦探
private investigator.
你拿到了私家侦探的执照  还不告诉我
You got your P.I.'s license... without telling me?
我学了个网上课程  昨晚学完了
I took an online course. Finished last night.
惊喜吧
Are you surprised?
能谈谈吗
Can we talk for a second?
失陪
Excuse me.
卡塞尔  私家侦探执照也不能改变什么
Castle, the P.I.'s license doesn't change anything.
地检官还是不会允许你跟随我们调查的
The D.A.'s still not gonna let you investigate with us.
这就是妙处啊
Oh, you see, that's the brilliant part.
我不会跟你们一起调查
I'm not going to be investigating with you.
不  我要与你们同时
No. Instead, I'm gonna conduct
展开独立的调查
my own parallel investigation alongside yours.
想得美  但这是行不通的
Nice try, but you know that's not gonna fly.
其实  行得通
Actually, it will fly.
作为...
You see, as a,
有执照的私家侦探  我有权
licensed P.I., I'm legally entitled
代表客户调查此案
to investigate this case on behalf of my client.
你的客户是谁
Ah. So who is your client?
抱歉  这是机密信息
I'm sorry. That's confidential.
抱歉  调查也是机密的
I'm sorry. So is this investigation.
他说得对
I'm afraid he's right.
不管你有什么执照  犯罪现场不对外开放
P.I.'s license or not, this crime scene is closed,
你得走了
so you're gonna have to go.
没事
That's fine.
反正我需要看的东西我都看到了
I've already seen everything I need to here anyway.
我会去别处开始调查了
I'll conduct my investigation elsewhere.
去哪啊
Elsewhere where?
抱歉  机密信息
I'm sorry, that's confidential, too.
他不是认真的吧
Is he serious?
我觉得他是  而且我好头疼
I think he is, and I think I'm getting a headache.
莱恩  你能去找找
Um, Ryan, see if you can get ahold
大楼的管理员吗
of this building's superintendent.
找找附近的监控摄像头
Look for any security cams
并努力联系她家人
and try to reach out to her next of kin.
埃斯波  我们去她工作的学校查查
Espo, you and I should go to the school that she worked for,
看他们能不能透露一些莎娜生活上的事
see if they can tell us anything else about Shana's life.
私家侦探这档子事你真不知道
You really didn't know about this P.I. thing?
不是  我看到他在电脑前一泡几小时了
No. I mean, I saw him spending hours on the computer,
但我以为他是在打游戏呢
but I just figured he was playing "Terra Quest."
你准备怎么做
So, what are you gonna do?
我也没什么办法啊
Well, there's not much that I can do.
我知道他这么做是为了跟我在一起
Look, I know that he's doioing this to spend time with me,
我不想伤他的感情啊
And I don't want to hurt his feelings.
或许不会有什么问题吧
I don't know, maybe it'll be...Harmless.
没问题
Harmless?
他可是卡塞尔啊
This is Castle we're talking about.
可他对案件和被害人一无所知
Okay, but he knows nothing about the case or the victim,
他能惹多少麻烦呢
so how much trouble can he be?
我们就要知道了
We're about to find out.
卡塞尔  你怎么过来的
Castle, how did you get here?
事实证明地铁早上的确比车快
Well, it turns out the subway really is faster in morning traffic.
不  我是问你怎么会来这里
No, I mean how did you get here,
来莎娜工作的学校
to the school where Shana worked?
邻居知道的信息不多
Oh, well, the neighbors didn't know very much.
所以我猜你下一步大概会来单位
I figured her work would be your next stop.
我听说过这里啊
So, I've heard about this place.
市里的直属学校
It's the feeder school in the city,
三岁的权贵之家后代  都在这里上学
the only place to be if you're 3 years old and connected.
那不是斯伯丁·埃利奥特吗
Isn't that Spalding Elliot over there?
全州最厉害的检察官
The state's top prosecutor.
他是司法部长的候选人呢
He's on the short list for attorney general.
后面那位  詹姆斯·卡尔曼  网络富豪
And behind him, James Kallman, internet billionaire.
我还在共乘车道看到了吹牛老爹
Even spotted Diddy in the carpool lane.
这地方聚集了这座城市的精英
Ah, this place is a bastion of the city's elite.
不知道被害人在这儿做了什么
I wonder what our victim did here,
她究竟被卷入了怎样的邪恶计划里
what foul scheme she was tangled in.
卡塞尔  你不能就这样跟我进去
Uh, Castle, you can't just follow me inside
然后偷听的我调查
and sit in on my interview.
可实际上...
Well, actually, um...
是我先到的这里
I was here first,
所以你得跟着我进去
So, really, you're following me.
莎娜是招生办主任
Shana was our admissions director.
家长  孩子  大家都很喜欢她
Parents, kids, everybody loved her.
你觉得她最近表现正常吗
How did she seem to you recently?
行为上和以前有什么不同吗
Any changes in her behavior?
其实  这点我并不清楚
Actually, I don't know.
过去几天她并没有来上班
She hadn't been around the past few days.
-为什么没有  -她之前一直在加班
- Why not? - She had been working long hours
为了最终确定新生的录取情况
to finalize admissions for our new students.
她上周才把录取通知书发出去
She just sent the acceptance letters out last week,
所以她最近几天就请假休息了
so she took the past couple of days off to recover.
既然录取通知书发出去了
If acceptance letters went out,
是不是说拒信也已经发了呢
does that mean rejection letters went out, as well?
我知道你是怎么想的
Look, I know what you're thinking,
确实  家长们会变得情绪激动
and, yes, parents can get a bit emotional,
特别是在他们的孩子被拒绝录取之后
especially when it comes to their kids being turned down.
不过事情从没有变得像现在这么严重
Nothing has ever risen to the level of something like this.
也许今年确实变得严重了
Well, maybe this year did.
有个东西你们得听听
There's something you guys got to hear.
你觉得你可以就这样毁掉我孩子的人生
You think you can ruin my kids' life?
婊子  我知道你住哪里
Bitch, I know where you live,
你给我小心点
and you'll never see me coming.
这是几天之前留在莎娜的语音信箱里的
This was left on Shana's voicemail a few days ago
也差不多正好描述了她的遭遇
and pretty much describes what happened to her.
马修斯博士  你能认出这个声音吗
Dr. Matthews, do you recognize this voice?
我听不出来
I'm afraid I don't.
好的  问问其他员工
Okay, check with the rest of the staff,
看看是否有人认得
see if anyone else does.
我们还需要一份学校电话的通话记录
We'll also need copies of the school's phone records,
以及收到拒信的家长名单
as well as a list of parents that received rejection letters.
没问题
Of course.
能也给我一份那个名单吗
Can I get a copy of that list, too?
我就当那是拒绝了
I'm gonna take that as a no.
其实也不算意料之外
Can't say that I'm shocked.
一帮手握大权的人根本听不得一个不字
A group of powerful people not used to hearing the word no.
拜托  卡塞尔  你真的觉得
Come on, Castle, you really think
被一所幼儿园拒收就能成为谋杀的动机
that rejection from preschool qualifies as motive for murder?
像这家一样的直属学校
With a feeder school like this one?
被这所幼儿园拒收就意味着
A rejection from here could mean
没法进入好小学
not getting into the "right" elementary school,
从而影响高中
which affects high school,
进一步会影响大学  我的天
which affects college, and, oh, my god.
父母为了孩子总会有疯狂的举动
Ah, people do insane things for their kids.
你会明白的
You'll see.
你要去哪里
Where are you off to?
回局里
Back to the precinct.
卡塞尔  如果我能选的话...
Look, Castle, if it was my choice --
你误会了
Oh, please.
我才不会想去局里呢
Why would I want to go to the precinct?
不  私家侦探的工作是在现场完成的
No, a P.I.'s work is done in the field,
而且我已经找到许多有用的线索了
and I've got lots of leads to follow up on.
好的  那晚上见
Okay. I'll see you tonight.
晚上见
See you tonight.
真不公平
So unfair.
私家侦探
A private investigator?
我发誓  长官  和我一点关系都没有
I swear, sir, I had nothing to do with this.
可他还是出现在你的罪案现场了
Yet he showed up at your crime scene!
我要提醒你  地方检察官明确地说了
Let me remind you, the D.A. was very explicit.
他上次跟黑帮合作那桩案子之后
Ever since he worked that case for the mob,
卡塞尔先生就再也不能参与我们的调查了
Mr. Castle can no longer take part in our investigations.
他没有参与
He's not.
严格意义上来说  他是在进行
I mean, technically, he's conducting
他自己的调查  因为他有了执照
his own investigation, and since he's licensed,
法律上说  我也没法做什么阻止他调查
legally, there's not much that I can do to stop him.
好吧  探长  让我再重申一遍
Okay, Detective, but let me be perfectly clear,
你不能帮他调查
you cannot help him either.
你们俩也听着了
And that goes for you, too.
-你说什么  -不许分享情报
- I'm sorry? - No sharing of information,
不许给他权限  什么都不行
no granting access, nothing,
不然你们会后悔的
or there will be hell to pay.
听明白了吗
Understood?
-是的  长官  -是的  长官
- Yes, sir. - Yes, sir.
很好
Good.
"他能惹多少麻烦呢"
"How much trouble can he be?"
相信我  等他发现他得自己调查这案子
Trust me, once he finds out that he has to work this case without me,
他就会觉得无聊  然后就不管了
he's gonna get bored, and he's gonna move on.
他自己一个人找到了被害者的学校
He found our victim's school without you.
是啊  不过那个很简单
Yeah, but that was easy.
他又没法查到财务状况
He doesn't have access to financials,
或是通话记录  或是街头监控的录像
to phone records, to street-cam footage.
他能查到多少东西
I mean, how far is he gonna get?
你知道什么情况最糟吗
You know what would really suck?
卡塞尔比我们先把案子破了
If Castle solved this case before we did.
那是根本不可能的
And this not possible.
是的  可是假如他成功了呢
Yeah, but what if he did?
那我们的耳根就别想清净了
Well, then we'd never hear the end of it.
不  是你的耳根不会清净了
Uh, no, you would never hear the end of it.
你才是那个每天要和他回家的人
You're the one who has to go home to that guy.
他根本不可能在我们之前把案子破了的
Listen, there is no way that he can solve this case before us.
你是谁
All right, who are you,
你为什么会抱着死者的狗
and what are you doing with a dead woman's dog?
你以为你能偷袭我吗
Think you can get the drop on me!
你根本不知道你对付的是谁
You don't know who you're messing with.
你是谁  为什么要跟踪我
Who are you? Why are you following me?
没法回答...说不了话
Can't answer...If can't talk.
我叫理查德·卡塞尔  我是...
Okay, my name is Richard Castle, and I'm --
-我可以给你看...  -别  别
- Oh, I can show you. - No, no!
胡椒喷雾剂
Pepper spray?!
你为什么要这么做
why did you do that?!
我以为你要掏枪出来
I thought you were reaching for a gun!
不是的  我是拿我的私人侦探执照
No, I was reaching for my P.I. license.
你是个私家侦探
You're a P.I.?
兄弟  真抱歉  快起来
Aw, man, I'm sorry. Come here.
我上周被抢劫了
I was mugged last week, all right?
你不能这样跟踪别人
You can't trail people like that.
对不起
Sorry.
我正在调查莎娜·贝克的谋杀案
I'm looking into the murder of Shana Baker.
什么
Oh, wait.
-莎娜死了  -是的
- Shana's dead? - Yes.
她是我的朋友
She was my friend.
凶手是谁
Hey, who killed her?
布莱恩·惠特曼  藤泽资本的高级合伙人
Brian Whitman, senior partner at Tenzer Capitol.
那通威胁电话是来自他的办公室
We traced the threatening call to his office.
这家伙是个大人物
The guy's a big shot
他的情绪问题比他的来头还要大
with even bigger anger-management problems,
上次直接把他的特斯拉撞向超他车的人
including slamming his Tesla into this driver who cut him off.
学校里有人认出他了吗
Anyone at the school recognize him?
没有  但我让警员拿他照片去莎娜住处排查
No, but I had unis show his picture around Shana's building.
他留下那通电话留言的同一天
The same day he left that voicemail,
邻居看到他猛敲她的门
neighbors saw him banging on her door,
嘴里全是污言秽语
Yelling obscenities.
他说他会回来的
He promised he'd be back.
我是有点...激动了
So I was a little...aggressive
因为贝克女士没让我儿子进那学校
when Ms. Baker didn't let my son into that school,
可那并不能证明我杀了她
but that doesn't mean I killed her.
"婊子  我知道你住哪里
"Bitch, I know where you live,
你给我小心点"
and you will never see me coming."
我觉得这好像是句威胁吧
That sounds like a death threat to me.
我当时比较激动
I was being dramatic.
那你向她开枪的时候是什么样
How were you being when you shot her?
你们不明白
Look, you don't understand.
陪审团的人也不会明白
And neither will a jury.
我没有理由要杀她
I had no reason to kill her.
关于我儿子的事  她改变主意了
She changed her mind about my son.
她决定让他入学
She decided to let him in.
惠特曼先生  我们有学校给的记录
Mr. Whitman, we have the school records.
这是两天前才发生的事
This just happened two days ago.
给他们打个电话  就能确认了
Call down there. You can check.
我还留着她给我写的信
I even have the letter she wrote me.
你儿子已经被拒绝了
Your son had already been rejected,
为什么莎娜要改变主意
So why would Shana change her mind?
我不知道
I don't know.
反正她就这么做了
She just did.
惠特曼的不在场证据被确认了
Whitman's alibi checks out.
谋杀案发生的时候  他去了香港
He was on an investment call to Hong Kong
参加一个投资项目
at the time of the murder.
学校也确认了他说的话
And the school verifies his claim.
莎娜的确改变了主意
Shana did reverse the decision on his son.
你觉得她是因为惠特曼的威胁害怕了吗
Do you think she gave into Whitman's threats?
不会  校长说莎娜是绝对不会妥协的
Nah. The headmistress said that Shana would never cut a deal.
如果她觉得受到了威胁
If she felt threatened,
她会告诉学校或者警察的...
she would have notified the school or the police...
除非还有更多隐情
unless there's more to this story.
再查查惠特曼
Let's dig into Whitman,
看看还有没有别的事能把他和莎娜联系起来
see if there's anything else that connects him to Shana.
他肯定隐瞒了什么
He's hiding something.
似乎被害人
Well, it looks like our victim
也隐瞒了一些事情
might have been hiding something herself.
据这张银行账单显示
According to this bank statement,
她在死前一天  从她的账户里
she withdrew $3,000 in cash out of her account
取出了三千块现金
the day before she died.
我想这不是她正常的取款吧
And I take it that's not her normal pattern of withdrawal.
的确不是
No, in fact,
这基本上把她的存款都取干净了
it nearly cleaned out her savings account.
莎娜·贝克为什么
So what would Shana Baker be doing
需要这么一大笔现金呢
that she needed that much cash?
莎娜要去别的地方
Shana was going out of town.
所以她才把闪闪交给我照看
That's why she wanted me to keep Sparkles.
我猜你跟狗相处得
I'm assuming you're better with dogs
比跟人相处得好
than you are with people.
-她去了哪  -不知道
- Where did she go? - No idea.
其实  整件事都挺奇怪的
In fact, the whole thing was sort of weird.
为什么
How so?
通常当她需要我照看闪闪时
Well, usually when I take Sparkles,
她会提前几周告诉我  但这次是突然的
she tells me weeks in advance, but this was really sudden.
她让我立刻带走他
I had to take him right away.
而且她通常也会告诉我她要去哪
And she always tells me where she's going,
但这次没说
but she didn't tell me this time.
你觉得她这次外出跟她的死有关吗
Do you think the trip had something to do with why she was killed?
鉴于她把狗交给你的第二天
Well, seeing as how she dropped her dog off with you
就被谋杀了
and the very next day she was murdered,
所以我想是的  这两件事有关系
my guess would be, yeah, the two are related.
你觉得她去了哪
Where do you think she went?
-卡塞尔  -帕穆特
- Castle! - Perlmutter.
你在干...
What are you...
你在看我的死者表单
you're looking at my victim's chart!
我只是在确认一下你都填对了
I'm just making sure you filled it out properly.
我得说一句  你的字写得真好
And may I say, for a man, you have exquisite handwriting.
快还给我
Oh, give it back!
等一下  听我说
Hey, hey, hey, look, look, look.
你可以帮我很大一个忙  帕穆特
You could make this a lot easier on me, Perlmutter.
就好像我活着就是为了帮你似的
Oh, because that's what I live for.
我认为死者在死前
I-I just believe that your victim traveled somewhere
去过什么地方
before she died.
尸检中有没有什么发现表明她去过哪
Is there anything in the autopsy that indicates where?
我宁愿死也不告诉你
I-I would rather switch places with her than tell you!
快还给我
Now... now, give me that!
-我警告你  卡塞尔  -找到了
- I am warning you, Castle! - Here it is.
胃里的东西...
Stomach contents...
两盎司花生  部分被消化的咸饼干
two ounces of peanuts, partially digested pretzels.
血液里有非处方镇定剂成分
Blood contains trace amounts of over-the-counter sedative.
她是在飞机上  她飞去了什么地方
She was on a plane. She flew somewhere.
谢谢你的帮忙
Thanks for your help.
这事没完
This isn't over!
-什么事  -我是贝克特
- What?! - It's beckett.
我们在死者的财务记录里发现些异常
We're trying to explain some anomalies
想要知道原因
in our victim's financial records.
有没有证据表明她最近去过什么远地方
Are there any signs that she traveled recently?
事实上
Well, as a matter of fact,
我刚跟你的作家丈夫讨论过这件事
I was just discussing that with the writer you married.
卡塞尔去了停尸房
Castle was at the morgue?
他怎么知道死者离开过城
How the hell did he find out our victim had left town?
不知道  不过帕穆特说她坐过飞机是对的
I don't know, but Perlmutter was right about the air travel.
根据运输安全管理局的记录
According to T.S.A. records,
莎娜两天前乘坐4:30的航班去了波士顿
Shana took a 4:30 flight to Boston two days ago.
她去波士顿干什么
What was she doing in Boston?
她没有家人或者朋友在那里
She doesn't have any family or friends there,
而且我问过学校
And I spoke to the school.
她去那也不是出差
She wasn't there for work,
她是用现金付的款
but she paid for the trip in cash
似乎她不想让别人知道这件事
like she was trying to keep it secret.
上面说她从波士顿回来的航班
It says here that her return flight from Boston
于昨天下午6点落地
landed yesterday at 6:00 P.M.
也就是她死前数小时
Just hours before her murder that night,
说明这次行程
meaning this mystery trip
或许跟她的死有关
might have something to do with her death.
是  你再看看这个
Yeah. And look at this.
根据她的手机通话记录  她下飞机后
According to her cell records, right after she landed,
立刻给《纽约文汇》新闻办公室打了电话
she made a call to the New York Ledger news desk.
一个幼儿园的招生主任
What's a preschool admissions officer doing
为什么要给《纽约文汇》新闻办公室打电话
calling the Ledger news desk?
或许她发现了什么有新闻价值的事
Maybe she uncovered something that she thought was a story.
但我跟他们确认过
But I checked with them over there,
没人记得跟她通过话
and nobody remembers talking to her.
我们得搞清楚她在行程中做了什么
We got to find out what she was doing during that trip.
是的  没错
Yeah, we do,
要赶在你老公之前  以免我们难堪
before your husband does and makes us all look bad.
我可以帮忙
I can help with that.
莎娜的信用卡所付的最后一笔钱
The last charge that Shana made on her credit card
是两天前在一家餐馆的账单
was for a lunch at a restaurant two days ago.
是在她出城之前
That's right before she left town.
她是跟这个叫妮可·莫里斯女人平分的账单
She split the bill with this woman, Nicole Morris.
她是哈里森-里德律所的一名律师
She's an attorney at Harrison and Reid.
这可是全国数一数二的律所
That's one of the top law firms in the country.
莎娜为什么要去见律师
Why would Shana be meeting with an attorney?
不知道
I don't know.
不过  一位名律师
But a high-powered attorney,
一段用现金支付的秘密行程
a secret trip paid for in cash,
再加一通打给新闻办公室的电话
and a phone call to a news desk.
这好像是个大阴谋
This is starting to smell like conspiracy.
虽然我也不想承认
Well, I hate to admit it,
不过这位小卡塞尔可能是对的
but baby Castle over here might be right.
无论是不是阴谋  既然莎娜临走前见过
Conspiracy or not, if this lawyer met with Shana
这个律师  那么她可能会知道些什么
just before her trip, she may know something about it.
我去哪能找到她
So where can I find her?
她的助手说她一整天都在外面见客户
Her assistant says that she's out all day with some clients,
不过你或许能在她3点约的人那里找到她
but you might be able to catch her at her 3:00.
-这是地址  -好的  谢了
- Here's the address. - Okay, thanks.
妮可·莫里斯
Nicole Morris?
我是贝克特探长  纽约警局的
Detective Beckett, NYPD.
我...
I...
卡塞尔
Castle?
你在这里干什么
What are you...doing here?
我在这工作
I work here.
欢迎来到理查德·卡塞尔侦探社
Welcome to Richard Castle Investigations.
你打算什么时候告诉我你有间办公室了
When were you gonna tell me that you had an office?
总有一天
Uh...eventually.
不  我们已经结婚了
No. We're married.
夫妻之间是没有秘密的
Married people tell each other things.
是的  可当你得知我拿到私家侦探执照时
Yeah, but you weren't exactly thrilled
你简直吓坏了
when I got my P.I. license.
因为之前你没告诉过我
'Cause you didn't tell me.
她在这里干什么
Now, what is she doing here?
死者出城前
Oh. She had lunch with the victim
跟她一起吃过午饭
right before the victim left town.
不不  我问你怎么找到她的
No, no, no. I mean how did you find her?
我查看了被害人的信用卡记录
Ah, I was checking the victim's credit card
想找她的机票费用信息以查出她要去哪里
for plane-ticket charges to see where she flew,
-结果却找到了餐费记录  -等等
- and instead I found a lunch charge -- - Wait a minute.
你查看了她的信用卡记录  怎么查的
You checked her credit-card records? How?
这个问题涉及到一个灰色区域
Okay, we're getting into kind of a gray area here,
只能说  这里提及到她的娘家姓
so let's just say it involved her mother's maiden name
和像模像样的假声
and a serviceable falsetto.
对不起  我还有别的约会
Uh, I'm sorry. I-I have another appointment.
还需要多久
Is this gonna take much longer?
马上就进去  莫里斯女士
Be right there, Ms. Morris.
探长  既然你已经来了
So, detective, so long as you're here,
是否愿意来旁听我的问话呢
would you care to sit in on my interview?
你打电话之前我根本不知道她被杀害了
I-I had no idea she had been killed until you called.
那真是  太让我震惊了
It was...quite a shock.
莫里斯女士  你对莎娜了解多少
Ms. Morris, - how well did you know Shana?
不是很了解
Not very.
我是几个月前为我女儿
I-I met her a few months back
参观伊斯特本学校的时候认识她的
when I toured Eastbourne's school for my daughter.
我们很合得来  但是我今年不打算申请
We hit it off, but I decided not to apply this year,
所以当她那天打电话给我时  我很惊讶
so I was surprised when she called the other day.
她说事情紧急  出城之前
She said it was urgent that she needed to meet
必须跟我见一面
before she left town.
她说过要去哪里吗
Did she say where she was going?
好像是波士顿
Boston, I-I think.
关于拉德诺大学的一些事
Something about Radnor University.
她有提过为什么要去那里吗
Did she mention why she was going there?
没有  坦白说
No, and frankly,
她提出那些问题以后
after the questions she was asking,
我根本不想知道她去干什么
I didn't really want to know.
为什么  她问你什么了
Why? What did she ask about?
谋杀
Murder --
特别是  马萨诸塞州
Specifically, felony statutes covering murder
关于谋杀的刑事法规
in the Commonwealth of Massachusetts,
什么算是协从谋杀
what qualifies as accessory to murder,
共谋谋杀
conspiracy to commit murder,
谋杀和过失杀人有什么区别
what's the difference between murder and manslaughter,
这方面的东西
that sort of thing.
我希望她是出于学术原因才感兴趣的
I was hoping her interest was theoretical,
但现在她死了  可能并不是那样
but now that she's dead, maybe it wasn't.
再一次感谢您  莫里斯女士  耽误您的时间
Again, thank you, Ms. Morris, for your time.
不客气
Of course.
如果需要帮忙随时给我打电话
Please call me if I can help in any way.
我会的
I will.
听见了吗  关于谋杀的刑事法规
Did you hear that -- felony law about murder?
你知道这表示什么吗
Do you know what this means?
是的  莎娜的这次远行
Yes, that there's a hell of a lot more
还有很多是我们不知道的
to Shana's trip than we know.
不管她在那里惹上了什么麻烦
And whatever trouble she got involved in up there,
我打赌那肯定跟着她回来了
I'm betting it followed her home.
好的  如果是那样的话  那么...
Okay, - if that's the case, then...
我...
I'm --
对不起  卡塞尔
Uh, I'm sorry, Castle.
我们不可以这样做
Uh, we shouldn't be doing this.
做什么
Doing what?
这种  你和我一起推理案件
Uh, this -- - you, me theorizing together.
这样不可以  尤其不能在这里
It's just -- it's not right, especially here,
因为私家侦探的事  我...
after this whole P.I. thing. I --
不  不要
No. Shh! Don't --
不要想这些
Don't think about it.
只要想想我们一起工作时的那种感觉
Just think about how it feels when we work together.
而且  这里只有我们俩
Besides, we have the place to ourselves.
谁会知道呢
Who's gonna know?
-是啊  -是啊
- Yeah. - Yeah.
-工作上的事  -不要接
- It's work. - Don't answer it.
不  我必须接
No, but I have to.
埃斯波  什么事
Hi, Espo. What's up?
之前你让我深入调查布莱恩·惠特曼
So, you asked me to dig deeper on Brian Whitman,
看能否发现与莎娜之间的联系
see if there were any other connections to Shana.
你绝对猜不到我发现了什么
Well, you'll never guess what I found.
不
No.
不  你说得对  那不可能是巧合
No, you're right, - that can't be a coincidence.
什么不可能是巧合
What's not a coincidence?
好的  把他带来
Okay, bring him in.
把谁带来
Bring who in?
对不起  宝贝  我得走了
I'm sorry, baby, I got to go.
你什么都不打算告诉我吗
You're not gonna tell me anything?!
你刚才还说夫妻之间没有秘密的
You said married people tell each other things!
你以为自己是谁  警官
Who the hell do you think you are, detective?!
为什么又带我回来
Why am I back here?!
惠特曼先生  请坐
Uh, Mr. Whitman, please.
你是个很慷慨的人
You know, you're a generous man.
你支持慈善事业
You support charitable causes.
你是众多受人尊敬的组织的董事会成员
You sit on the board of numerous esteemed organizations,
其中包括拉德诺大学
including Radnor University.
那又怎样
So?
在莎娜·贝克死之前  她去了拉德诺
So just before Shana Baker died, she took a trip to Radnor.
这件事你知道吗
You know anything about that?
抱歉  我帮不上忙
Sorry. Can't help you.
我认为你可以的
I think you can.
她的行程  你在学校董事会的地位
Her trip, your position on the school's board,
她帮你儿子进入那所幼儿园
and her help in getting your son into that preschool --
我认为这三件事之间有联系
I think those three are related.
你来告诉我们联系是什么
And you're gonna tell us how,
不然迟早我们也会查出来的
or we're just gonna find out anyway.
那时我们会以阻碍司法罪逮捕你
Then we're gonna take your ass down for obstruction
也可能是协从谋杀
and maybe accessory to murder.
更别提当那所幼儿园得知
Not to mention what's gonna happen
你拒绝协助调查
at that preschool when they find out
他们一名员工的谋杀案
you refused to cooperate on an investigation
结果会如何吧
of one of their employees' deaths.
我认为你的孩子
I don't think your kid
不会在那里待多久了
is going to be enrolled there for much longer.
好吧  听我说
Okay, okay, okay. Look, look, look.
是她来找我的  好吗
She came to me, okay?
她想让我帮她在拉德诺做点事
She wanted me to pull some strings at Radnor,
作为回报  她接收我的孩子入园
and in return, she got my kid in.
她希望你做什么事
What strings did she want you to pull?
她让我联系教导主任
She wanted me to contact the dean of students
告诉他莎娜要去见他
to tell him Shana was coming to see him
她需要他帮忙做些事情
and that she needed help with something.
她到底需要他帮什么忙
And what exactly did she need help with?
她不肯告诉我
She wouldn't tell me.
她只让我给教导主任打电话
She just asked me to make the phone call to the dean.
我只知道这些  我发誓
That's all I know, I swear.
没事了吧
So we're good, right?
我儿子不会被开除吧
My son's still in?
教导主任证实莎娜昨天的确在那里
The dean confirmed that Shana was there yesterday,
要求查看拉德诺的校警文件
requesting access to Radnor campus police files.
校警文件  哪一起
Police files? Which ones?
他不知道  不过据档案室的人说
He didn't know, but according to their records room,
她查看的是从1999年开始的案件
she looked through incident reports from 1999.
她为什么要查看15年前的案件报告
Why would she be looking at 15-year-old incident reports?
我打赌卡塞尔肯定知道
I bet Castle knows.
你真的假的啊
Are you kidding me?
这次他绝不可能赶在我们前面
There is no way he's ahead of us on this.
他先去了停尸间  又先找到了律师啊
Hey, he got to the morgue before us and that lawyer.
莱恩  他是机智  但还没这么机智
Ryan, he is resourceful, but he is not that resourceful.
他不是把你骗到手了吗
He got you to marry him, didn't he?
打给他
Call him.
看看他查的怎么样了
We'll see where he's at.
我才刚刚说不让他参与
I just cut him out of the case.
怎么打给他问他进度啊
I can't call him and ask him what he knows.
那就别明着问
Then don't ask him.
你不是侦探吗  用点手段
You're a detective. Detect.
谢谢你送饭来
Thank you for picking up dinner.
我怕你被私家侦探的微薄薪水饿死了
I didn't want you to starve on that P.I. salary.
那么  你的第一个案子查的如何了
So, how is your first case going?
我有没有告诉你  我今天被胡椒水喷了
Did I tell you - I got pepper-sprayed today?
你怎么说的跟好事似的
You say that like it's a good thing.
是啊  我现在是有点卡住了
Yeah. I mean, now I'm kind of stuck.
我知道死者去了一趟拉德诺大学
I know our victim took a trip to Radnor university.
只是还不知道为什么
I just have no idea why.
我侵入了她的社交媒体帐号
I hacked into her social-media accounts.
等等  你知道怎么侵入社交媒体帐号
Wait. You know how to hack into social-media accounts?
侵入这个词可能重了
"Hacking" might be overstating it.
她的所有密码都是闪闪  她的狗的名字
Her password for everything is "Sparkles," Her dog's name.
重点在于  没有警方的帮助
Point is, without police resources,
我能做到的也就只有
the best I can do is
浏览她朋友们在网上的发布
go through her friends' online posts
试着去找其中和拉德诺大学的联系
and look for some connections to Radnor university.
-找到了吗  -只有一条
- Are there any? - Just one thing.
但那是15年前的事了
But it happened 15 years ago.
我完全不知道这之间到底有什么联系
I have no idea if it's even relevant.
真希望我知道贝克特的进度如何了
I just wish I knew what Beckett had.
理查德·卡塞尔侦探所
Richard Castle investigations.
宝贝
Hey, babe.
只是问个好  你干什么呢
Just checking in. What you doing?
在办公室闲着呢  你呢
Oh, just hanging out at the office. How about you?
他有个办公室
He has an office?
我就是想知道你过得怎么样
Uh, just wondering how your day's going.
好
Good.
其实是非常好
Really good, actually.
你呢
How about yours?
我也挺好的
Yeah, mine's... Good, too.
是非常非常好
Uh, really, really good.
那就好  真好  应该说我真的很好
That's good. Great. I should have said great.
我的一天好极了
Mine's great.
真好  那
Great. That's --
好吧  那晚上见
Okay, so, I'll see you tonight.
晚上见
I'll see you tonight.
他肯定知道了什么
He knows something.
她肯定知道了什么
She has something.
你得把消息套出来
And you have to find out what.
我会把消息套出来
And I'm gonna find out what.
我回来啦  你今天回来的挺早啊
Oh, hey, there. You're home early.
等不及见到你了嘛
Hey. I couldn't wait to see you.
回来时我在路上买了瓶红酒
So, I picked up a bottle of wine on the way home.
你最喜欢的哦
It's your favorite.
那真是
Oh, that is...
一大杯酒啊
such a big glass.
有什么好事吗
What's the occasion?
没有啊
No occasion.
只是想用这个方式
I just figured this would be a great way
缓解一下你一天辛苦工作的疲劳
for you to unwind after a long day at work.
你真好
Oh, that is so nice.
你的杯子呢
And where's your glass?
在那边
Uh, it's over there.
那我来帮你倒酒吧  好吗
Well, why don't we top that off for you, shall we?
等我们
Once, uh, we get all nice
舒舒服服的了
and relaxed and unwind --
好的
There we go --
你也可以给我讲讲你的一天了吧
You can tell me all about your day.
好啊
Yeah.
等等
Wait a minute.
你不会是想借酒
You're not trying to ply me with wine
从我这套出关于案子的情况吧
to find out what I know about this case, are you?
当然不是
Of course not.
这不会是  你想要干的事吧
That's not what you're trying to do, is it?
-不是  -好吧
- No. - Okay.
因为如果你是想要知道我的进度
Because if you were trying to find out what I know,
那就说明你是卡住了
that would mean you're stuck.
我没有卡住
I am not stuck.
很好  因为我也没有卡住
Good, because I'm not stuck either.
-你确实知道什么  -你确实知道什么
- So you do know something. - So you do know something.
-也许吧  -也许吧
- Maybe. - Maybe.
好了  这太傻了
All right, this is crazy.
如果我们都查到了什么
If we both have something,
不如互换吧
why don't we just trade?
卡塞尔  我不能这么做  你知道的
Castle, I can't. You know that.
不能这么做
Oh, "Can't."
以前那个穿皮夹克骑摩托的
What happened to that rebellious girl
桀骜不驯的女孩哪去了
with the leather jacket and the motorcycle?
她会说不能这么做这种话吗
Would she say "Can't"?
她现在是喝着高级红酒的执法人员了
She enforces the law now and drinks expensive wine.
那想想死者吧
Then think about our victim.
你真的要让一些无聊的规矩
Are you really gonna let a couple of silly rules
阻碍你为莎娜伸张正义吗
stand in the way of bringing Shana justice?
好吧
Okay, fine.
仅此一次  为了死者
We'll do it just this once... for her.
-你先说  -你先说
- You first. - You first.
我们同时说吧
We'll go at the same time.
-准备好了吗  -好了
- Ready? - Yeah.
她在调查关于拉德诺大学的
She was looking into old police
-警方案件记录  -莎娜的男友
- records at radnor university. - Shana had an old boyfriend
-死在了拉德诺大学  -等等
- who died at Radnor university. - Wait.
莎娜的男友死在了拉德诺大学
She had an old boyfriend who died at Radnor university?
-什么时候的事  -15年前
- How long ago? - 15 years.
他的名字叫杰夫·韦兰
His name was Jeff Whalen.
他在派对上醉酒跌出了窗户
He drank too much at a party and fell out a window.
如果说她在调查警方案件记录
If she was looking into old police records...
而且还对谋杀法律感兴趣
And interested in homicide law...
她肯定是认为他的死
She must have thought that his death
并非意外
was more than just an accident.
她是在调查谋杀案
She was investigating a murder.
但这调查却害死了她
And somehow that got her killed.
天呐  真怀念这个
Oh, my god. I missed this.
昨晚真棒
Last night was amazing.
等等  你是在说
Wait, are you talking about
交流办案进展  还是说
the put-together we did on the case, or...?
后面这个
That.
但交流办案进展也很棒
But the put-together, that was pretty amazing, too.
都好久没这样做过了
It's been forever since we tried that.
我都忘记你这么有创意了
I forgot how creative you can get.
我们说的不是案子了吧
Oh, we're not talking about the case anymore, are we?
莱恩
Hey, Ryan.
很好  好的
Great. Okay.
要多久文
How long before the fil--
它才能到
before it gets there?
什么能到
Before what gets there?
-你刚才是要说文件对不对  -不对
- You were about to say "Files," weren't you? - No.
昨晚你给莱恩发了短信让他去
Oh, you texted Ryan last night about Shana's old boyfriend
给你调莎娜男友的案件记录
and told him to get those old police files for you...
-什么  -而你却和我在床上
- Wha...? - While you were in bed with me.
我  莱恩  我马上到
I -- Ryan, I'll be right over.
你得让我看一眼记录吧
Well, you're gonna let me take a look at those files, right?
这才公平
I mean, that's only fair.
卡索尔  我不能这么做
Castle. I can't.
那可越界了
That would be crossing the line.
你昨晚好像不怎么在意界限啊
You didn't seem to care about lines last night.
昨晚  什么都行
No, last night, it was anything goes.
是的  卡塞尔  昨晚很棒
Yes, Castle. And it was great.
算了吧
Come on.
我们都明白只能仅此一次
We both know it was just a one-time thing.
我还以为咱俩来电了呢
You know, I thought we had something special!
是那份文件吗
Is that the file?
看来你凌晨两点那时的灵感还是有收获的
Yeah, and it looks like your 2:00 a.m. hunch paid off.
不管怎样  你这么晚在干什么
What were you doing up so late, anyway?
我在研究那个案子
I was working on the case.
我不知道莎娜在那份报告里
Well, I don't know - what Shana was looking to find
要找的东西是什么
in that report,
但文件是关于一个派对的证人证词
but it refers to witness statements
莎娜的男朋友
taken at the party
杰夫·韦兰在这次派对中死掉了
where Shana's boyfriend, Jeff Whalen, died.
但这份证词
But the witness statements,
还有作证的那些人
as well as the list of people who gave them,
都失踪了
they're all missing.
-文件被篡改了吗  -看上去应该是的
- The file's been tampered with? - It looks that way.
我打给拉德诺大学时  他们说这几页
When I called over to Radnor, they said that those pages
肯定是丢失了的
must have been "lost"
当十年前他们把档案数字化的时候
when their records were digitized 10 years ago.
那个当时写这份报告的官员呢
What about the officer that wrote the original report?
几年前就去世了
Passed away a few years back.
如果信息丢失了的话
Okay, if the information is missing,
莎娜在报告里知道了什么而被人灭口了呢
then what did Shana learn from this report that got her killed?
据在档案室工作的人说
According to the guy in the records department,
莎娜看完了档案后
when Shana finished with the archive,
她问了校友办公室在哪里
she asked for directions to the alumni office.
我给那里打了电话
I-I placed a call over there,
但他们大概半个小时后才上班
but they don't open for another half an hour or so.
对了  昨晚和卡塞尔怎么样了
Oh. How'd it go with Castle last night?
他在我们前头还是落后于我们
Is he ahead of us or behind us?
我们肯定在他之上
Uh, we're definitely on top of him.
查不了警方的文档
Without access to those police files,
我肯定被他们甩到后面去了
they are gonna leave me in the dust.
我以为你当私家侦探是想和贝克特一起办案
I thought you became a P.I. to work with Beckett.
什么时候这变成比赛了
When did it become a competition?
当她把我和她创造的美好
When she took something beautiful
分享给了另外一个男人
that we'd built together and shared it with another man.
什么
What?
从调查的角度来说
Investigatively speaking.
但我好像找到了赶上他们的办法
But...I may have found a way to catch up.
我在搜索任何提到
I have been looking for any mention
莎娜男朋友死亡的消息
of Shana's boyfriend's death --
报纸  公共档案及其他地方我都查了
wading through newspapers, public records, and the like.
看一下这个
And check this out.
是从《拉德诺大学日报》里找到的
It's from the Radnor University Daily.
你注意到这则广告上有不对劲的地方吗
Do you notice anything unusual about this ad?
大家都害怕千年虫的这件事吗
That people were ever actually afraid of Y2K?
是的  还有这则广告在上半版版面
Yes, that, and the ad is above the fold.
我在校报工作过
I worked on my school paper.
版面布局入门知识
That's layout 101 --
永远都不要把广告放在头版的上半版
You never place an ad above the fold on the front page --
除非有什么东西在最后一刻发生了变化
Unless something changed, last-minute,
多出来一个空要补上
creating a space to fill.
比如头条新闻缩短了
Like the lead story was shortened.
有些东西被撤掉了
Something was pulled from it
就在出版之前
just before they published,
我敢保证这肯定和这个案件有关
and I bet it relates to this case.
你可以查出这篇报道的作者
You could track down the reporter,
看他能不能告诉你
see if he could tell you.
可这条新闻的署名是工作人员
Except the story is credited to "Staff."
但肯定有其他人知道
But there is someone else who knows.
-谁  -那个最初要求
- Who? - The person who ordered
缩短文章的人
the article shortened in the first place --
编辑
The editor.
弗兰克·杰克逊
Frank Jackson?
对  校友办公室的人说
Yeah, the guy at the alumni office
莎娜一进门
said that Shana came in
就要求找到所有他的联系方式
requesting all of his contact information.
弗兰克·杰克逊
Frank Jackson?
怎么听起来这么熟呢
Why does that sound so familiar?
因为他现在是《纽约文汇》的一名记者
Because he is now a reporter at the New York Ledger.
他就是莎娜被杀害那天联系过的人
That's who Shana was calling the day she died.
我知道是怎么回事  十五年前
And I can tell you why -- 15 years ago,
弗兰克·杰克逊是
Frank Jackson was the president
入会严格的虎爪社交俱乐部主席
of the exclusive Tiger Claw Social Club,
就是这家俱乐部当时举办了那场派对
the organization that hosted the party
莎娜男朋友意外身亡
where Shana's boyfriend died.
为了调查  莎娜给弗兰克打了电话
So, Shana called Frank as part of her investigation.
她知道如果他是当时俱乐部的主席
She knew that if he was president of that club,
他当晚肯定在派对上
he must have been at the party that night.
如果其中有所隐瞒  他肯定知道内情
And if there was a cover-up, he would've been in on it.
那他就有可能是凶手
Then he could be our killer.
不好意思  杰克逊先生
Excuse me! Mr. Jackson!
我想和你谈谈你编辑过的一篇文章
I-I wanted to talk to you about an article you edited
就是关于15年前一名学生
about 15 years ago about a student who died
在虎爪俱乐部身亡
at the Tiger Claw Social Club.
对不起  我要迟到了  下次吧
Sorry. I'm late. Another time.
你省略了文章中的一些内容  对吧
You left something out of that article, didn't you?
关于杰夫·韦兰死亡的真相
Something about - how Jeff Whalen really died.
你说你是谁来着
Who'd you say you were again?
我是理查德·卡塞尔
I'm Richard Castle.
我是调查莎娜·贝克谋杀案的私家侦探
I'm a private investigator working the Shana Baker murder.
好  不在这谈  我知道附近有个地方
Okay. Not here. I know somewhere nearby.
更隐秘一些
It's more private.
我们还没找到杰克逊
We still can't find Jackson.
他没在公寓
He's not at his apartment,
也没接电话
and he's not answering his phone.
好  发全境通告
Okay. Put out an A.P.B.
如果他是杀害莎娜的凶手他可能会出逃
If he's Shana's killer, then he may try to run.
《纽约文汇》的电话
Yo. That was Ledger.
杰克逊的一位同事说他看见
One of Jackson's coworkers said that he saw him
杰克逊一小时前和一个长得像卡塞尔的人
leave the building about an hour ago
离开了大楼
with some guy who looked like Castle.
卡塞尔找到了杰克逊吗
Castle found Jackson?
他完全不知道那人有多危险
And he has no idea how dangerous he is.
该死  卡塞尔  快接电话啊
Damn it, Castle, answer.
他怎么就不能不插手这件事呢
Why can't he just stay out of this?
我什么时候不管过这些事情
When have I ever stayed out of anything?
谢天谢地
Oh, thank God.
你在这里做什么
Now, what are you doing here?
我懂规矩  但考虑到和我一块来的人
I know the rules, but, uh, given who I'm with,
我想我们可以破个例
I thought we might make an exception.
我知道这天会来的
I knew this day would come.
当莎娜那晚打电话给我时
When Shana called the other night,
我几乎松了一口气
I was almost relieved.
就告诉贝克特探长
Just tell detective Beckett
你告诉我关于莎娜打电话的原因
what you told me about why she called.
是关于她的男朋友
It was about her boyfriend.
她想知道杰夫·韦兰
She wanted to know how Jeff Whalen really died
那晚在拉德诺大学的真正死因
that night at Radnor university.
杰夫那晚烂醉
Jeff was pretty wasted.
他上楼去透气
Uh, he went upstairs to get some air.
我记得接着就听到一声尖叫
And the next thing I remember was the scream.
我没有看到发生了什么
Now, I didn't see what happened,
但我知道杰夫摔下窗户时
But I know Jeff wasn't alone in that room
他不是独自一人在房间
when he fell out the window.
你认为他是被谋杀的吗
You think that he was murdered?
我只知道第二天
All I know is the next day,
我迫于压力要修改那条新闻
I was pressured to change the story.
有人让我把任何提到
I was told to take out any mention
是谁和杰夫一同在房间的信息删除
of who was in the room with him.
等等  谁给你施压
Wait. Who pressured you?
某个大人物
Someone big.
他说他只是想保全他儿子的名誉
He said he was just trying to protect his son's reputation.
他说他可以毁了我的人生
He told me he could ruin my life...
或是助我成就大事
or he could do great things for me.
我当时只是个孩子  我吓坏了
I was a kid, and I was scared.
我想既然警察已经宣布那只是个意外
And since the cops already said that it was an accident,
何必毁了两个人的人生呢
I figured why ruin two lives?
只不过那不是场意外
Only it wasn't an accident.
当我发现警方的调查被人做了手脚时
By the time I had realized the investigation had been...
我已经成了帮人掩盖谋杀的从犯
rigged, I had already helped to cover up a murder.
如果你站出来
And if you had come forward,
你的记者事业也就结束了
your career as a journalist would be over.
没错
Exactly.
可我不能再逃避下去了
I can't hide from it anymore, you know.
他们在保护谁  弗兰克
Who were they protecting, Frank?
谁把莎娜的男友推出了窗外
Who pushed Shana's boyfriend out the window?
上一个问我这个问题的人死了
Last person I told that, um, wound up dead.
你确定你想知道吗
I mean, you sure you really want to know?
咱们把话说明白
Let me get this straight.
你认为联邦检察官斯伯丁·埃利奥特
You think federal prosecutor Spalding Elliot
杀害了莎娜·贝克
killed Shana Baker?
这正是事实所指
The events support it, sir.
据杰克逊先生说  莎娜找过他之后
According to Mr. Jackson, right after Shana spoke to him,
就直接去找埃利奥特对质
she went to confront Elliot about his role
问他是否和她男友的死有关
in her former boyfriend's death.
他孩子在她所在的学校上学
And he's a parent at her school,
所以她知道他的联系方式
so she knew where to find him.
众所周知
Look, it -- it's no secret
埃利奥特正欲大展宏图
that Elliot is being groomed for bigger things,
也许他必须要将莎娜封口
so maybe he needed to silence Shana
以防她毁了自己
to keep her from destroying him.
探长  如果你要指控
Detective, if you're gonna go after
纽约市最出色的联邦检察官
the top federal prosecutor in New York,
只凭一个违反了职业道德的记者的几句话
you're gonna need more than just the word
是远远不够的
of a compromised journalist.
得有铁证
You're gonna need bullet-proof evidence,
可你没有
and you don't have it.
如果我们能证明埃利奥特在案发现场呢
What if we can place Elliot at the crime scene?
我们找到了一个有DNA证据的烟头
We found a cigarette butt with DNA evidence on it.
你准备怎么跟他做比对呢
Which you're gonna match to his how?
如果他是凶手  他肯定不会自愿提供DNA样本
I doubt if he's gonna volunteer his DNA if he's guilty.
我们会想办法的
We'll find a way.
谨慎为之  警探
Tread lightly, detective.
你的对手可不容小觑
You're hunting big game here.
在我们获得更多证据前
And until we have a stronger case,
绝不能引起注意
we cannot afford to attract any attention,
也就是说  卡塞尔先生
which means, Mr. Castle,
你跟这个案子不得有半点关系
you cannot be involved in this at all,
即使你是私家侦探也不行
even in your - private-investigator capacity.
头  我们能查到这一步多亏了
Sir, we never would have gotten this far without --
不  她说得对
Oh, no. Actually, uh, she's right.
规定就是规定
Rules are rules.
实际上
As a matter of fact,
我现在都不应该在这
I shouldn't even be here right now.
这比我想象中容易多了
Well, that was easier than I expected.
是啊
Yeah.
丢啊
Come on.
好了
There.
DNA证据拿到了
One sample of damning DNA evidence coming right up.
抱歉  神探  这次不能让你了
Sorry, Sherlock. Not this time.
下面该由专业人士接手了
Pros will take it from here.
一个烟头
A cigarette butt.
这有什么含义吗
Is that supposed to mean something?
这是我们在莎娜·贝克的谋杀现场取回的
It was recovered at the scene of Shana Baker's murder.
初步的DNA检测证实这是你留下的
Preliminary DNA tests indicate it's yours.
这不可能
That's not possible.
可能  因为你就在现场
It is, because you were there.
你杀了她  埃利奥特先生
You killed her, Mr. Elliot.
这太荒唐了  我根本就不认识她
That's ridiculous. I didn't even know her.
我干吗要杀她
Why would I kill her?
因为她知道
Because she knew the truth
那晚在派对上发生的事情
about what happened that night at the party,
她知道杰夫·韦兰谋杀案的真相
about Jeff Whalen's murder.
我们知道她找到了你
We know that she tracked you down,
当她找你对质时  你杀了她灭口
and when she confronted you, you had her silenced.
听着
Okay, listen.
没错  她是找到了我
Okay. She did track me down.
她那晚就等在
And she practically accosted me
我办公室门口堵我
in front of my office the other night.
可我把真相都告诉她了
And I told her the truth, all right?
没错  杰夫坠楼那晚
That -- that I -- yes, I was in the room
我是在屋里
the night that Jeff fell,
但我没有推他
but I did not push him.
那是个意外  警方报告中都写了
It was an accident. It's in the report.
那你父亲为什么要掩盖这件事
Then why did your father cover it up?
因为他知道真相并不重要
Because he knew that the truth wouldn't matter,
大众会仅仅因为我当时也在屋内
that I would be convicted in the court of public opinion
而认定我有罪
just for being there,
那样一来  我的政治生涯还没开始
and that my political career would be over
就要结束了
before it ever started.
于是你就掩盖了事实
So you swept it under the rug,
当莎娜找到你
and then when Shana came along --
她  你认为她是第一个为这事找我的人吗
She -- do you -- do you think she was the first?
多年来我的敌人
Listen, my enemies have been circling
一直追着这件事不放
around this story for years.
你知道为什么媒体一直没有报道此事吗
And you want to know why the media's never run with it?
因为根本就没什么好报道的
Because there's nothing there.
直至现在
Until now.
-有人陷害我  -埃利奥特先生
- I'm being set up. - Mr. Elliot --
莎娜说有人联系她
Shana said somebody contacted her
说是我把杰夫推下楼的
and told her that I pushed Jeff.
他们鼓励她去"查出真相"
They urged her to "Look into the truth."
然后她就死了
And then -- then she ends up dead?
接着你们就在现场找到这个
And you find this at the scene?
你声称有人在陷害你
You're claiming someone is framing you?
我是罪案检察官
I am a criminal prosecutor.
你们难道真的认为我会笨到
Do you honestly think that I would be stupid enough
在现场留下这种证据吗
to leave a piece of evidence like this behind?
我通过对抗企业的贪婪打响了名号
Look, I make my name fighting corporate greed.
我的政治野心也众所周知
And my political ambitions are -- are no secret to anyone.
这个  你们还不明白吗
This -- don't you see?
这是我的敌人毁掉我的最佳方法
This -- this is the perfect way for my enemies to destroy me.
你这推论有一个问题  埃利奥特先生
Okay, there's only one problem with that theory, Mr. Elliot.
想要陷害你
In order to frame you,
这个人必须得知道你十五年前
a person would need to know that you were there
出席了那个派对
at that party 15 years ago
还必须知道莎娜在回家一小时前
and know that Shana Baker had just come from seeing you
去见过你
an hour earlier.
也许有更简单的解释
Maybe there is a simpler explanation.
这根本就不是针对你的阴谋
There is no conspiracy against you.
你就是杀害她的凶手
You killed her.
我不可能杀她
You know, I-I couldn't have killed her
因为那晚在参加筹款活动
because I was at a fundraiser that night.
我们查过了  你是十一点到的
Yeah, we checked into that. You got there at 11:00.
莎娜十点半就遇害了
Shana was dead by 10:30.
我发誓
I swear to you.
-我是被陷害的  -抱歉
- I am being set up. - I'm sorry.
恐怕我们别无选择  只得逮捕你
I'm afraid I have no other choice but to arrest you for --
等一下
Wait!
他说的是实话
He's telling the truth.
斯伯丁·埃利奥特不是凶手
Spalding Elliot is not our killer.
我叫你别碰这个案子
Was I not clear when I told you
我说得还不够清楚吗
to stay away from this case?!
好吧  我知道你不开心
Okay, I can see you're upset,
但是我保证  你马上就会明白
but I promise -- in a moment, you'll understand.
杰瑞米
Jeremy?
这位是杰瑞米
This is Jeremy.
他是死者的朋友兼狗保姆
He's the victim's friend and dog sitter.
怎么  杰瑞米是证人吗
Oh, so, Jeremy is some sort of a witness?
不是
Uh, not quite.
杰瑞米  给我
Jeremy, if I may...
小狗  小狗是证人
Oh, the dog? The dog is the witness?
卡塞尔先生
Mr. Castle --
瞧好吧
Just watch.
卡塞尔  你干什么
Castle, what are you doing?
证明他的清白
Proving this man's innocence.
卡塞尔
Castle...
埃利奥特先生  抱歉了
Mr. Elliot, if I may...
求你  别
Please. No!
我记得在看埃利奥特先生的档案时
See, I remember reading in a profile of Mr. Elliot
他对长毛犬有极度过敏反应
that he has a severe allergy to long-haired dogs.
被害人的公寓到处都是狗毛
And the victim's apartment was covered in dog hair.
对头
Exactly.
这种人根本就不能
Now, does this seem like the kind of man
待在莎娜住处
who could wait in Shana's apartment,
更别说在等的时候抽烟了
let alone smoke a cigarette while he did so?
求你了
Please!
倒也是  不过他可能是装的
No, but, I mean, he could be faking the whole thing.
求你了  再这样  就出疹子了
Please! Please! Get him out of here before the hives start!
不是装的
I think that ship has sailed.
疹子的确装不出来
Okay. Yeah. Definitely not faking that.
这是斯伯丁·埃利奥特在莎娜被害当晚
Here is Spalding Elliot arriving at the fundraiser
抵达慈善晚宴的照片
the night of Shana's death.
看吧  他脸上没有红色的疹子
Note the lack of red splotches on his face.
他如果直接从莎娜住处
There's no way that he came
去那里  看起来肯定不是这个样子
straight from her apartment looking like that.
也就是说莱恩之前猜对了
Which means Ryan nailed it before.
这的确是个阴谋
This is a conspiracy.
莱恩  你往阴谋那个方向思考了
Ryan, you played the "C" card?
你不在
Well, I mean, um, you weren't around.
总得有人接班
Somebody had to step up.
这阴谋如果想成功
Okay, for this setup to work,
得有人让莎娜行动起来  告诉她掩盖真相的事
someone had to activate Shana and tell her about the cover up.
那样的话  她的死会将调查方向引到
Right. That way, her death would create an investigative path
埃利奥特身上
that led straight to Elliot.
把她的死栽赃在他身上
Setting him up for her murder.
我认为我们要找的人
My guess is we're dealing with
是个天价掮客
some kind of big-money fixer,
藏在暗处的职业杀手  迈克尔·克莱顿那种
a shadow-y gun-for-hire, Michael Clayton type.
不管是谁在犯罪现场放置了埃利奥特的DNA
Well, whoever planted Elliot's DNA at the crime scene
总得有办法拿到烟头
had to have gotten the cigarette butt from somewhere.
也就是说那人在某个时候跟埃利奥特有交集
Which means they had to intersect with Elliot at some point.
如果我们找到了时间和地点
If we can figure out where and when --
"我们"  卡塞尔先生
"We," Mr. Castle?
不是吧
Really?
可我
But I --
我都给你们送大礼了啊
I brought him -- on a silver pla--
好吧
Fine.
我自行撤退
I'll show myself out.
我们追寻的是同一件事  正义
We were all after the same thing -- justice.
麻烦的是  在我这
Trouble is, when it came to me,
正义女神有别的打算
Lady Justice had different plans.
当贝克特和伙计们接近凶手的时候
While Beckett and the boys closed in on the killer,
我已如昨日垃圾倒进阴沟
I had been to the gutter like yesterday's trash.
不太公平啊
It just didn't seem fair.
说得对
You're right.
是不太公平
It's not fair.
贝克特
Hey! Beckett.
我在听一些录制的笔记
I was just, uh, listening to some notes I made
查案时录的  你来做什么
for the ca-- I just -- what are you doing here?
我们用检查了那个烟头
You know, we took another look at the cigarette butt --
有埃利奥特DNA的那个
The one with Elliot's Dna.
在上面发现了烧烤汁的残留
It turns out it had traces of barbecue sauce on it.
我记得你说不能跟我分享查案情况
I thought you said you couldn't share.
是不能
I can't.
但如果不是你分享了
But if you hadn't shared,
我们还会把埃利奥特当成凶手
Then we'd still be looking at Elliot as our killer.
再说这里只有我们俩
And besides, we got the place to ourselves,
谁会知道呢
So who's gonna know?
我想埃利奥特最近吃烤肉了
So, I assume Elliot has had barbecue recently.
上周  在上城区一家烤排餐馆
Just last week at a rib joint uptown.
我们看了监控录像
We scrubbed the security video,
你绝对猜不到是谁
and you'll never guess who we found
在烟灰缸里找埃利奥特的烟头
digging through the ash can for one of Elliot's cigarette butts.
不会吧  那就是我们的迈克尔·克莱顿
No way. That's our Michael Clayton?
被幕后黑手雇佣
Likely hired by whoever is behind all of this
成为莎娜的朋友  透露消息给她
to befriend Shana, whisper in her ear,
要她去调查
and urge her to investigate.
并确认我们追查指向拉德诺大学的线索
And who ensured - we followed the trail to Radnor.
真希望能在你们给这人戴手铐时
Oh, I wish I could see the look on their face
看看这人脸上的表情
when you slap the cuffs on them.
也许你可以看到
Yeah, well, maybe you can.
卡塞尔先生
Mr. Castle.
我接到紧急电话  让我来  说与莎娜·贝克有关
I got an urgent call to meet you here regarding Shana Baker?
是的
Yes.
有最后一个问题  莫里斯女士
Yes. Just one final question, Ms. Morris.
谁雇你杀了莎娜·贝克
Who hired you to kill Shana Baker
然后陷害斯伯丁·埃利奥特
and frame Spalding Elliot?
你在说什么
Wh-what are you talking about?
你知道的
I think you know.
那是你  收集埃利奥特的烟头
That's you retrieving Elliot's cigarette butt
以便你能把其放在犯罪现场
so you could plant it at the crime scene
在你杀了莎娜之后
after you killed Shana.
妮可·莫里斯
Nicole Morris,
你因谋杀莎娜·贝克而被捕
you're under arrest for the murder of Shana Baker.
我一直听说哈里森-里德律所
You know, I always heard Harrison and Reid
是家超赞[杀手]的律所
were a killer law firm.
终于知道原因了
Now I know why.
结案
Case closed.
你认为我们会知晓妮可·莫里斯为谁卖命吗
You think we'll ever know who Nicole Morris works for?
她不会说的
Ah, she's not gonna tell us.
但我们发现了几笔巨额汇款
But we did find several large payments
转至她的账户
wired to her account,
埃利奥特势要找到源头
and Elliot is determined to find their source.
是我的话  也会劲头十足
Well, I would be determined, too.
如果不是因为小狗闪闪
That guy would be spending time in jail
他要在监狱待很长时间呢
if it wasn't for a dog named sparkles.
还多亏了私家侦探卡塞尔
And a P.I. named Castle.
真为你骄傲
I'm proud of you.
我本以为你是闹着玩的
I just -- I thought this was another one of your larks,
为了消磨时间  但你让我刮目相看
a way to kill time, but...you impressed me.
我都有点为自己刮目相看了
You know, I kind of impressed myself.
为新书找到了各种点子
I got all sorts of ideas for my new book.
只有一件事没能如愿
Just one thing didn't work out as planned.
你知道如果依着我
You know that if this was up to me
我们会并肩工作的
that we would be working together, right?
知道  但不能依着你  我们也无法共事
Yes, but since it's not and we can't,
我在想  如果我把私家侦探这差事
I was wondering how you'd feel if I...
继续一段时间  你怎么想
kept with this for a while.
别动
Don't move.
这是什么
What's this?
我的答案
It's my answer.
我明天要戴着这个去上班
I'm so gonna wear this to work tomorrow!
接着看  还有呢
Keep going. There's something else.
也许你可以用它寻找下一个客户
So, maybe you can use that to locate an actual client.
我找到了更想看的东西
I think I see something I like better already.
你想进卧室一起分享吗
You care to go into the other room and...Share?
有一个条件
On one condition.
-什么  -帽子要一直戴着
- What? - The hat stays on.